Guide to the Sandi Carroll Papers Relating to Early Productions of August Wilson's Seven Guitars
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Sandi Carroll Papers Relating to Early Productions of August Wilson's Seven Guitars
1995-1996
JWJ MSS 188
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
2.09
(5 boxes)
The papers consist of scripts, notes, rehearsal schedules, venue descriptions and other materials that document the productions of August Wilson's Seven Guitars in Boston, San Francisco, Los Angeles, and on Broadway in New York City, in 1995-1996. The material also provides a record of how characters and dialogue in the play were changed and developed during these productions. Also included are several corrected proofs of the script as it was being prepared for publication.
Carroll, Sandi
Arrangement
Arranged by production and type of material.
Sandi Carroll
Sandi Carroll is an American actor, educator, director and producer. She received a Bachelor's of Fine Arts degree from Boston University, and a Master's of Fine Arts degree from the University of Virginia. In 1995 and 1996, Carroll worked as August Wilson's assistant and dramaturg on early productions of his play Seven Guitars.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
This collection may be housed off-site at Yale's Library Shelving Facility (LSF). To determine if all or part of this collection is housed off-site please check the library's online catalog, Orbis; material for which the location is given as "LSF" must be requested 36 hours in advance. Please consult with Beinecke Access Services for more information.
Description of the Papers
The papers consist of scripts, notes, rehearsal schedules, venue descriptions and other materials that document the productions of August Wilson's Seven Guitars in Boston, San Francisco, Los Angeles, and on Broadway in New York City, in 1995-1996. The material also provides a record of how characters and dialogue in the play were changed and developed during these productions. Also included are several corrected proofs of the script as it was being prepared for publication by Penguin USA.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Sandi Carroll, 2016.
African American dramatists; American drama -- 20th Century; Dramatists, American; Dramaturges -- United States; Theater -- Production and direction; Theater -- United States; Scripts (documents); Dramatists -- United States -- 20th Century; Dramaturges -- United States -- 20th Century; Carroll, Sandi; Wilson, August, 1945-2005; Wilson, August ( Seven guitars)
- Production of Seven Guitars at the Huntington Theatre Company, Boston, Massachusetts
  Biographical / Historical
  The production opened on September 8, 1995
  - Script changes with notes, 1995 September (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Teacher study guide, [1995] (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Black-and-white portrait photograph of August Wilson by Eric Antonioiu, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Reviews (photocopies), 1995 September (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Scripts
    - 1995 September 14 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
    - 1995 October 2 (Box 1, Folder 7-8)
    - 1995 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 9-10)
    - 1995 November 6 (Box 1, Folder 11-12)
  - Script changes, 1995 October (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
  - "Old [script] pages", 1995 September (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Autograph manuscript notes taken by Sandi Carroll for August Wilson during rehearsals/performances, 1995 October (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Production of Seven Guitars at the American Conservatory Theater (A.C.T.), San Francisco, California
  The production opened on November 15, 1995
  - Production binder contents, 1995 October 29 (Box 2, Folder 17-19)
    Scope and Contents
    Includes publicity card; rehearsal calendar; company cast and personnel lists; theater information; correspondence regarding events with August Wilson; typescript script notes annotated by Sandi Carroll; script changes from rehearsals and previews; set ground plan
  - Script binder contents, 1995 August 8 (Box 2, Folder 20-22)
    Includes script with dividers indicating acts/scenes; with autograph annotations by Carroll
  - Script, 1995 November 16 (Box 3, Folder 23-24)
  - A.C.T. educational guide, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Reviews (photocopies), 1995 November (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Production of Seven Guitars at the Center Theatre Group/Ahmanson Theatre, Los Angeles, California
  The production opened on January 17, 1996
  - Production binder contents, 1996 January 6 (Box 3, Folder 27-29)
    Includes publicity cards and brochure; rehearsal calendar; company cast and personnel list; Center Theatre Group information; typescript script and script notes annotated by Sandi Carroll
  - Script, 1996 March 6 (Box 3, Folder 30-31)
  - "August old/new [script] pages", 1996 January (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - "August old [script] pages", 1996 January (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - "August new [script] pages", 1996 January (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Production program, 1996 January 17 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    With issue of Show Monday of the Orange County Register from 1996 January 15
- Production of Seven Guitars at the Walter Kerr Theatre, New York
  The production opened on March 28, 1996
  - "LA/NY" script binder, 1996 January 2 (Box 4, Folder 36-39)
  - Production binder contents, 1996 February 10 (Box 4, Folder 40-41)
    Includes production program; rehearsal schedule; contact sheet of producers, cast, etc.; publicity schedule and correspondence; typed script with notes from rehearsals; and telefaxscimiles from Sandi Carroll to Lloyd Richards
  - "Old [script] pages", 1996 March (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - "New [script] pages", 1996 March (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Revised script, 1996 March 28 (Box 4, Folder 44-45)
    Includes autograph note, signed from Wilson to Carroll on title page
  - Telfacsimile regarding the Outer Critics Circle Award, 1996 April 16 (Box 4, Folder 46)
- Penguin USA publication of script
  - Page proofs, 1996 November 22 (Box 5, Folder 47-48)
    Includes typescript cover memorandum dated November 27, 1995, from Rena to Arnold regarding page proofs for the author's review
  - Corrected page proofs, 1996 January 16 (Box 5, Folder 49-50)
    Includes unsigned typescript cover note regarding changes in script
  - Typescript list of questions regarding "galleys" with autograph manuscript answers, 1996 January 5–1996 January 16 (Box 5, Folder 51)
    Typescript notes on changes to be made to script proofs, with autograph notes by August Wilson
  - Typescript note from Carroll to Wilson regarding stage directions, 1996 August 28 (Box 5, Folder 52)
    Includes typescript costume inventory, perishable list; description of the setting; sound cue list; prop list; and credits for Broadway production
- Seven Guitars guitar picks (2), undated (Box 5, Folder 53)